Preliminary Guide to the German Poster and Postcard Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
German poster and postcard collection
1970-1990
MS 1810
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
33.5
The German Poster and Postcard Collection consists of approximately 2400 posters and 150 postcards from East and West Germany depicting countercultural, political, and propaganda themes from the 1970s to 1990. A small number of newspapers and pamphlets are included in the collection.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased by Yale University Library for Manuscripts and Archives, 1993.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The German Poster and Postcard Collection consists of approximately 2400 posters and 150 postcards from East and West Germany depicting countercultural, political, and propaganda themes from the 1970s to 1990. A small number of newspapers and pamphlets are included in the collection.
Conditions Governing Access
Box 8, postcards, must be used under the supervision of a Public Services staff member at the front table.
Counterculture -- Germany; Propaganda, German; Germany (East); Germany (West); Postcards; Posters
- Inventory
  - Posters
    - Selections for class use
      - East German (DDR), 1970s-1980s (Box 1A)
      - West German (BRD), 1970s-1980s (Box 1B)
      - West German (BRD), 1970s-1980s (Box 1C)
    - West German political counterculture, 1970s-1980s (Folder 2A–2E)
    - West German political counterculture and international political counterculture, 1970s-1980s (Box 5D, Folder 3A–3E, Folder 4A–4E, Folder 5A–5C)
      - Additional material (Box DR139F1)
      - Additional material (Box DR139F2)
  - West German political counterculture and first free elections, 1970s-1980s, 1990 (Box 6)
  - East German propaganda, 1970s-1980s (Folder 7A–7F)
  - Postcards [West German political counterculture], 1970s-1980s (Box 8)
  - Posters, West German political counterculture, 1970s-1980s (Box 9)
    - Additional material (Box 10)
    - Additional material (Box 11)
    - Additional material (Box 12)
    - Additional material (Box 13)